<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Integrity on Warren&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/data-integrity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Integrity on Warren&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/data-integrity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned from a Cascade Deletion Incident</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/12/cascade-del/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/12/cascade-del/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;setting-the-scene&#34;&gt;Setting the Scene&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One evening, a project manager reached out to inform me that some data appeared to be missing from our system. Upon investigating, I discovered that an unintended cascade deletion had occurred due to the use of &lt;code&gt;on_delete=models.CASCADE&lt;/code&gt;. This resulted in the deletion of not only the target data but also several related records, which were critical to the system&amp;rsquo;s integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-restoration-process&#34;&gt;The Restoration Process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Restore from Backup:&lt;/strong&gt; I quickly connected with our Site Reliability Engineer (SRE) to retrieve the most recent data backups. After confirming the integrity of the backups, I restored them to a staging environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delta Sync:&lt;/strong&gt; After confirming the backup’s integrity, I performed a delta restoration, syncing the backup with the current database to recover the lost data while preserving recent changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Code Fixes:&lt;/strong&gt; I updated the models, replacing &lt;code&gt;models.CASCADE&lt;/code&gt; with safer options like &lt;code&gt;models.PROTECT&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;models.SET_NULL&lt;/code&gt; to prevent accidental deletions in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lessons-learned&#34;&gt;Lessons Learned&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be Cautious with&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;on_delete&lt;/code&gt;: Understand the cascading impact when cleaning up or modifying attributes that affect related records.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backups Matter:&lt;/strong&gt; Regular backups are essential for quick recovery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Test Thoroughly:&lt;/strong&gt; Ensure changes are tested with edge cases, especially when they involve data relationships.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Better Monitoring:&lt;/strong&gt; Implement more granular monitoring and alerting for destructive changes to the database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This experience was a wake-up call to double down on best practices, including database integrity checks, better testing, and comprehensive backups. Mistakes happen, but the goal is to learn from them and improve the system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
